A Guide to the Max Bergmann papers, Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research Scientific Staff FA001
Rockefeller Archive Center
Max Bergmann papers, Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research Scientific Staff
1886-1961 (bulk 1941-1945)
bulk
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
Bergmann, M. (Max)
FA001
7.31 Cubic Feet 19 boxes
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in six series: 1) Personal, 2) Laboratory Administration, 3) Research, 4) Publications, 5) Declassified Reports and 6) Lantern Slides. See the individual series descriptions for more details on the contents. of each series.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Received from the Rockefeller University in 1981.
Appraisal
Duplicate reports and circulars were discarded. Also, in cases where preservation photocopies were necessary due to the poor condition of the original document, the original document was discarded.
Related Materials
The American Philosophical Society (APS) Library has additional papers of Max Bergmann. A copy of the collection description and inventory for the records housed at the APS Library can be found in Series 1, Folder 1. An abstract of the collection is also available on the APS Library website at: http://www.amphilsoc.org/library/mole/b.htm#Bergmann.
Biographical / Historical
Max Bergmann was a German biochemist. He was born in Furth, Bavaria on February 12, 1886. After receiving his Ph.D. from the University of Berlin in 1911, he worked closely as an assistant to Hermann Emil Fischer from 1911 to 1919. Together, they laid the foundation for scientific knowledge of proteins, carbohydrates, and tannins. Following the suicide of Fischer, Bergmann accepted a position as Vice–Director and Head of the Department of Organic Chemistry at the Kaiser Wilhelm Institute for Fiber Chemistry in Berlin. In 1921, he moved on to serve as Director of the Kaiser Wilhelm Institute for Leather Research until 1933. When the conditions in Germany grew too hostile, he emigrated to the United States and became an Associate Member of the Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research where he continued as a pioneer of applied sciences focused on proteins and protein–splitting enzymes, as well as the chemistry of carbohydrates and fats. In 1937, he became a full member of the Institute. He died at Mount Sinai Hospital in New York on November 7, 1944. At the time of his death, he was working under contract with the U.S. Office of Scientific Research and Development to benefit the national defense during World War II. This research focused on the synthetic, analytical, and inorganic problems in chemical warfare and B–4 toxicity, especially mustard gases.
Chronology
1886 Born February 12, 1886 in Furth, Bavaria.
1907 B.S. from the University of Munich.
1911 Ph.D. from the University of Berlin.
1911–1919 Assistant to Emil Fischer at the University of Berlin.
1915 Son Peter G. Bergmann is born.
1917 Daughter Esther M. Bergmann is born.
1919–1921 Vice–Director and Head of the Department of Organic Chemistry at the Kaiser Wilhelm Institute for Fiber Chemistry in Berlin.
1921–1933 Director of the Kaiser Wilhelm Institute for Leather Research and Honorary Professor for Leather Chemistry and Biochemistry at the Technical Hochschule in Dresden.
1928–1933 Elected President of the International Society of Leather Chemists
1934–1937 Associate Member of the Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research.
1937–1944 Full Member of the Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research.
1940 Becomes a naturalized U.S. citizen May 18, 1940.
1944 Dies November 7, 1944 at Mount Sinai Hospital, New York.
Scope and Contents
This collection primarily documents the laboratory research and administration of biochemist Dr. Max Bergmann during his tenure at the Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research, now the Rockefeller University, from 1934 until his death in 1944. The records are particularly focused on the research he conducted in the 1940s on problems of interest to the U.S. Armed Forces, namely the synthetic, analytical, and inorganic problems in chemical warfare and B–4 toxicity, especially mustard gases. Records consist mostly of laboratory research notes, notes on related scientific literature, research progress reports, correspondence with colleagues and administrative officials, administrative circulars and memoranda, reprints of Bergmann publications, and receipts of classified reports and scientific samples. Research topics of interest include World War II chemical warfare research, Selective Service deferments for scientists, policies and procedures of the Office of Scientific Research and Development and the National Defense Research Committee, and the “brain drain” or significant emigration of scientists and technologists to the United States from Europe as a result of hostile conditions prior to World War II. The collection also contains a minimal amount of biographical material, including Bergmann's personal correspondence, documents relating to Bergmann's funeral, and photographs.
File Plan
Former Classification: I 450 B454
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for scholarly research with select materials restricated, as noted.
World War II; Chemical warfare; Biochemistry; Japan; Bergmann, Martha; Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research; Bergmann, M. (Max); United States. Armed Forces
- Personal, 1886–1961 (bulk 1933–1946); bulk; 1; 0.2 Cubic Feet
  Arrangement:
  Alphabetical by subject or format.
  Summary:
  This series consists primarily of Bergmann's correspondence from 1934–1944 documenting his appointment to the Rockefeller Institute of Medical Research (RIMR), arrangements for his arrival in the U.S., efforts to gain immigrant status, retiring allowances, and RIMR administrative matters. Correspondents include Simon Flexner, H. T. Clarke, and J. B. Conant. The series also documents Bergmann's death and his funeral service held at RIMR, including a biographical memoir written by Joseph S. Fruton that was used in the Memorial Minute adopted by the Board of Scientific Directors and a short address delivered by Fruton at the funeral service. Other biographical records consist of copies of documents submitted for naturalization, including Bergmann's birth certificate, prison record, and marriage certificate, all of which are in German. Also included are several photographs of Bergmann, a listing of periodicals and books from Bergmann's library that were made available for purchase by Joseph Fruton following Bergmann's death, and a copy of the collection description and inventory for the Max Bergmann papers housed at the American Philosophical Society Library.
  - American Philosophical Society Library: Max Bergmann Papers, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Diaries, See logbooks
  - Bergmann, Martha, 1944–1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Biographical Synopses, 1944, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1933–1944; 2 folders (Box 1, Folder 4, Folder 5)
  - Funeral Service, 1944–1945 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Naturalization Documents, 1886–1945 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Photographs, [192?]–1944 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Physical Examinations, 1924?, 1934? (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Scientific Periodicals and Books from the Library of Dr. Max Bergmann, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Laboratory Administration, 1934–1946 (bulk 1941–1944); bulk; 2; 3.5 Cubic Feet
  This series has been retained in its original order and the original file folder labels were used. Bergmann arranged his folders alphabetically by subject. Within the folders, he roughly arranged his records either in reverse chronological order or by subject depending on the type of document. For instance, the correspondence files tend to be in reverse chronological order, whereas more general files are in alphabetical order by subject, which is usually typed on the right side of the document. His arrangement within folders, however, is not always consistent. The Office Memorandum folders, for instance, combine order by memorandum number within a rough overall alphabetical order. Bergmann also maintained a system of extensive cross–references within these files.
  This series documents Max Bergmann's administration of his laboratory at Rockefeller University while it was under contract with the U.S. Office of Scientific Research and Development to conduct research of benefit to the national defense during World War II. This research focused on the synthetic, analytical, and inorganic problems in chemical warfare and B–4 toxicity, especially mustard gases. This series consists primarily of correspondence, receipts, and forms tracking the routine exchange and use of scientific reports. Correspondence with other scientists also documents the exchange of samples, as well as directions for specific tests, preparations of samples, and brief discussions of reactions and test results. Also included is a significant amount of correspondence and forms related to the Espionage Act Oaths of Secrecy and Selective Service deferments for the scientists working in Bergmann's laboratory. The Literature files consist of reports and reprints from other scientists, along with Bergmann's handwritten notes about what he read. Also included in this series is an incomplete set of Administrative Circulars and Office Memorandum documenting the policies and procedures of the Office of Scientific Research and Development and the National Defense Research Committee. The majority of memos are located in Box 5, but some are filed alphabetically by subject throughout the series.
  Eight folders in this series have a correlating folder with the same title in series 5: Declassified Reports, the contents of which were declassified by the U.S. Army after this collection was archivally processed. Researchers may wish to review both the folder in this series as well as the one with the same title found in series 5 for a full view of material on a given subject.
  - A, 1940–1944 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Account “K” NDRC, 1942–1945 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - B, 1942–1945 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bergmann Appointments: Consultant Official Investigators, 1941–1943 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Bergmann, Max Dr., 1940–1944 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Bowman, Robert A., 1941–1943 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bush, Vannevar, 1940–1944 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - C, 1934–1946 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Cannan, R. K., 1942–1944 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Chadwell, Harris M., 1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Campbell, Mrs. Marcia D., 1943 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Cohen, Barbett, 1942–1944 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Conner, Ralph A., 1942 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Contract No. OEMsr–313, 1942–1945 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Contract Symbol 881, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Cope, Arthur C., 1942–1944 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Cori, Carl F., 1942–1944 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - D, 1940–1945 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - DB 3 Reagent: Directions for use of, 1942–1943 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Deferments Log, 1944–1945 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Directions, 1934, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Discussion Log, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Du Vigneaud, Vincent, 1942–1944 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - E, 1942–1944 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    File Plan
    Former Classification: I 450 B454, Box 2
  - Espionage Act, 1940–1945 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - F, 1941–1944 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Failey, Crawford F., 1942–1944 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Friedenwald, Jonas S., 1942–1944 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Fruton, Joseph S., 1942–1946 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - G, 1940–1945 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Gasser, H. S., 1941–1944 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Golumbic, Calvin, 1941–1945 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - H, 1941–1944 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - I, 1941–1945 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Indexes to Reports, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - J, 1942–1944 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - K, 1942–1944 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - KB 16: Correspondence, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Kelley, Dr. Louise, 1942–1945 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - L, 1942–1944 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Literature I, 1943–1945 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Literature II: A. G. Ogston and R. A. Peters, 1940–1943 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Literature III: E thru L, 1942–1944 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Literature IV: Miscellaneous, 1942–1943 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Literature V: A thru D, 1942–1944 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Literature VI: M thru P, 1942–1944 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Literature VII: Michael Heidelberger, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Literature VIII: Edgewood Arsenal, 1943–1944 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Literature IX: Howe Laboratory, 1942–1944 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Literature X: Salter, William T., 1942–1944 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Literature XI: Skipper, H. E., 1943 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Literature XII: Porton Reports, 1942–1944 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Literature XIII: Q thru Z, 1941–1944 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Literature XIV: Wilmer Institute, 1942–1943 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - M, 1941–1944 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Mail, 1941–1944 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Material Received, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - McClean, Franklin C., 1942–1944 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - McMaster, Philip D., 1942–1944 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Me, 1942–1944 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Meetings
    - Invitations, 1941–1944 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Minutes and Notes, 1942–1944 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Moore, Stanford, undated, 1942–1946 (Box 4, Folder 15, Box 5, Folder 1)
  - N, 1941–1946 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Nagy, Stephen, 1942–1944 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Northrop, John H., 1941–1944 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - O, 1941–1945 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Office Memorandum (2 folders), 1940–1945 (Box 5, Folder 6, Folder 7)
  - P, 1941–1944 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Pending, 1942–1946 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Penetration Work, 1943–1944 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Q, 1942–1944 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - R, 1942–1945 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Renshaw, Birdseye, 1943–1945 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Receipts
    - A reports, 1942–1944 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - B reports (2 folders), 1941–1945 (Box 6, Folder 1, Folder 2)
    - Bushnell Weekly News Letters, 1944–1945 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - C reports, 1942–1945 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - CMR Reports, 1943–1945 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1942–1946 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Moore, Stanford, 1943–1944 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Progress Reports, 1942–1945 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Reports Returned to Washington, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Special Reports (2 folders), 1942–1945 (Box 7, Folder 3, Folder 4)
  - Reports
    - 9:5:1, 1942–1945 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      Former Classification: I 450 B454, Box 7
    - Borrowed Log, 1944–1945 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - CMR, 1943–1945 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Disposition of Extra Copies, 1942–1945 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Received, A–B–C, 1942–1945 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Received Log, 1943–1945 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Received, Other Progress Reports (3 folders), 1942–1945 (Box 8, Folder 1, Folder 2, Box 7, Folder 11)
      Former Classification: I 450 B454, Box 7 (2745) and Box 8 (2746)
    - Returned to Washington, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - S, 1941–1945 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - S 1130 Compound, 1942–1943 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Samples: Received and Sent Out, 1942–1944 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Selective Service Deferment (2 folders), 1941–1945 (Box 8, Folder 7, Folder 8)
  - Shriner, R. L., 1943 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Smith, Homer W.
    - I. Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1942–1945 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - II. Invitations to Meetings, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - III. Reports, 1942–1945 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - IV. Samples Sent, 1942–1944 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Stahmann, Mark A.
    - General, 1942–1945 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - C.W. Agents Program, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Stein, William H., 1942–1946 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Stewart, Irvin, 1942–1945 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Stock, C. Chester, 1942–1944 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - T, 1942–1945 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Telephone Numbers, 1941, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Substituted Thioureases: Yoe and Overholser, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Travel, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - U, 1942–1943 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - V, 1942–1944 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Vickery, H. B., 1942 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - W, 1942–1944 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - W Agent, 1943–1945 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - X–Y–Z, 1942–1945 (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Research, 1940–1946; 3; 1.1 Cubic Feet
  This series documents the research Max Bergmann and his scientific staff conducted under contract with the U.S. Office of Scientific Research and Development to benefit the national defense during World War II. This research focused on the synthetic, analytical, and inorganic problems in chemical warfare and B–4 toxicity, especially mustard gases. Records consist primarily of informal and formal progress reports, as well as the laboratory and literature notes of two of Bergmann's key scientific staff members, William H. Stein and Stanford Moore.
  - British Reports, undated, 1941–1942 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Drafts and Corrections
    - KB–16 Report, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - N–Mustards Reports (8 folders), [194?] (Box 10, Folder 4, Folder 5, Folder 6, Folder 7, Folder 8, Folder 9, Folder 10, Folder 3)
    - Penetration Report, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - S–Mustards Reports (7 folders), [194?] (Box 10, Folder 12, Folder 13, Folder 14, Folder 15, Folder 16, Folder 17, Folder 18)
  - Formal Progress Reports
    - Chemical Reactions of Divinyl Sulfone, H Sulfone, and Divinyl Sulfoxide, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Chemical Reactions of the Nitrogen Mustards, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Chemical Reactions of Semi–H and H, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - The Chemistry of Q, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - The Chemistry of Sulfonium Salts Related to H, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - N–Nitroso–N–Chloroethylcarbamic Acid Methyl Ester (TL 186), 1942 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - The Penetration of Vesicant Vapors into Human Skin, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - The Reactions of Amine Mustards with Chemical Constituents of Biological Systems, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - The Reactions of DH, TL 146, TL 329, and TL 145 with Some Chemical Constituents of Biological Systems, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Some Reactions of Mustard Gas with Proteins and Proteolytic Enzymes, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Informal Progress Reports
    - December, 1941 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - January – February, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - March – April, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - May – June, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - July – August, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - September – October, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - November – December, 1942 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - January – February, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - March – April, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - May – June, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - July – August, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - September – October, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - November – December, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - January – February, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - March – April, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - May – June, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - July – August, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - September – October, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - November – December, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Laboratory Scientific and Volunteer Staff, 1934–1945 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Moore, Stanford
    - Laboratory Notes, 1942 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Literature Notes, 1942 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Report Summaries: Copy Instructions, 1942–1943 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Stein, William H.
    - Chapter 19. Chemical Reactions of the Sulfur and Nitrogen Mustards, undated, 1946 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Laboratory Notes, 1942 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Laboratory Notes, 1943–1944 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Literature Notes – 1130, 1942 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Literature Notes – H (Chemical), 1940–1945 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Literature Notes – H (Physiological), 1942–1944 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Literature Notes – H and Divinyl Sulfone, 1941–1944 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Literature Notes – MFA, undated, 1942–1944 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Literature Notes – N–Mustards, 1942–1944 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Literature Notes – Other Agents, undated, 1942–1944 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Literature Notes – Q and Related Compounds, undated, 1943 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Literature Notes – W Agent, undated, 1943 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Special Notes, 1942 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - TL 110, undated, 1943 (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Publications, 1911–1946; 4; 1 Cubic Feet
  The reprints were maintained in their original order based on sequential numbers assigned to each. This numerical order generally corresponds to chronological order. Several un–numbered reprints dating from 1926 to 1946 that were not incorporated in the original order can be found at the end of the series. The bibliography of his collected papers, reprint index, and reprint lists do not correlate with the order of the reprints and should not be relied upon as an access tool.
  This series documents the published works of Max Bergmann. It includes a bibliography of his collected papers, a card catalog index of his reprints dating from 1911 to 1926, and two lists of reprints.
  - Collected Papers: Bibliography, [1946+] (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Reprint Index, 1911–1926 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Reprint Lists, [1926+, 1941+] (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Reprints
    - 1–10, 1911–1921 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - 11–20, 1921–1922 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - 21–30, 1922–1923 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - 31–40, 1923–1924 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - 41–50, 1924–1925 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - 51–60, 1925 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - 61–70, 1925–1926 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - 71–80, 1926 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - 81–90, 1926–1927 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - 91–100, 1928 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - 101–110, 1928–1929 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - 111–120, 1929 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - 121–130, 1929–1930 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - 131–140, 1930 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - 141–150, 1930–1931 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - 151–160, 1931 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - 161–170, 1932 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - 171–180, 1932 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - 181–190, 1932–1933 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - 191–200, 1933–1934 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - 201–210, 1934 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - 211–220, 1934–1935 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - 221–230, 1936–1937 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - 231–240, 1937–1938 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - 241–250, 1937–1939 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - 251–260, 1939–1940 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - 261–270, 1940–1941 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - 271–280, 1941–1942 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - 281–290, 1942–1945 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Un–numbered, 1926–1946 (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Declassifed Reports, 1940-1945; 5; 0.4 Cubic Feet
  Access:
  Researchers are required to use the stamped declassified photocopies in Box 15. The originals are in Box 16 and are closed.
  This series contain documents that were declassified by the U.S. Army after this collection was archivally processed. The contents of each folder in series 5 originated from a correlating folder of the same name in either series 2 or series 3. Researchers may wish to review both the folder in this series as well as the one with the same title found in a previous series for a full view of material on a given subject.
  Arrangement note:
  The folders in series 5 are in the same order as the correlating folders in series 2 and 3.
  - Literature II: A. G. Ogston and R. A. Peters, 1940-1943 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Literature III: E thru L, 1942-1944 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Literature IV: Miscellaneous, 1942-1943 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Literature V: A thru D, 1942-1944 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Literature VI: M thru P, 1942-1944 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Literature XII: Porton Reports, 1942-1944 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Literature XIII: Q thru Z, 1941-1944 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - M, 1941–1944 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Research: British Notes, undated, 1941–1942 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Literature Notes – H (Chemical), 1940-1945 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Literature Notes – H (Physiological), 1942-1944 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Literature Notes – H and Divinyl Sulfone, 1941-1944 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Literature Notes – MFA, undated, 1942-1944 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Literature Notes – N–Mustards, 1942-1944 (Box 15, Folder 14)